<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Soapbox Systems</title>
    <description>The truth never damages a cause that is just. 
</description>
    <link>https://soapbox.systems/</link>
    <atom:link href="https://soapbox.systems/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <pubDate>Wed, 30 Sep 2015 16:01:11 -0400</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 30 Sep 2015 16:01:11 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v2.4.0</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>An Auditable API</title>
        <description>&lt;h2 id=&quot;an-auditable-public-api&quot;&gt;An Auditable Public API&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;overview&quot;&gt;Overview&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The goal of this document is to describe the auditing process and the relevant aspects of a system that verifies that a web server is faithfully serving public statements included in a block chain. 
The reference implementation along with demonstrative test cases of the API are available &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/soapboxsys/ombudslib&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The goal of providing public auditing is to give clients that consume a third party’s block chain data some autonomny in judging the trustworthyness of that third party. 
The tangible goal is to remove some of the attacks a malicious API server can mount against a client.
While not providing anonymity, this extension lets clients prove to themselves and others that the API server is not manipulating data.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;status-of-this-document&quot;&gt;Status of This Document&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the initial discussion of a design that is subject to change. 
While this is not an RFC, the intention behind this document is to describe the extension completely so that it is reproducible and well understood.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nick – September 2015&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;contents&quot;&gt;Contents&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Definitions&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Requirements
    &lt;ol&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Server Descriptions&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Client Descriptions&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ol&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Signatures&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Inclusion Proofs&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Managing Certificates&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Disclaimer&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;definitions&quot;&gt;Definitions&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Throughout this document the term &lt;code&gt;record&lt;/code&gt; is used regularly. 
A record defined here is a single public statement that has been included in the block chain.
As of September 2015, the Ombuds protocol defines two types of records: bulletins and endorsements.
The schemas of these records and their encodings can be found &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/soapboxsys/ombudslib&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;requirements&quot;&gt;Requirements&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A simple read-only HTTP JSON API server produces responses that contain data to clients that request it.
In this traditional setup, the client is dependent on the server honestly sending data.
If the server operator has malicous intent, he can manipulate existing data, withhold data, or fake the existence of data.
To prevent these things from occuring on servers running Ombud’s API, it is nessecary to require two things of API servers and four things of API clients.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;api-servers-must&quot;&gt;API Servers MUST:&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Provide signed responses to all requests.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Provide proofs of inclusion for all atomic records in its database.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Respond on a best effort basis to all requests from API clients.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;api-clients-must&quot;&gt;API Clients MUST:&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Select unpredictable challenges.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Regularly audit the API server.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Publish failed audits to peers.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Stop using the API server if it misbehaves or fails an audit.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If an API server and a group of Ombuds clients obey these requirements, then the clients can collectively rely on a single API server to faithfully provide them with accurate information. 
So long as the Ombuds clients can communicate amongst each other they will be able to adapt to a changing landscape of third parties of unknown reliablity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In brief, the audit process works as follows: &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;An API client connects to the server and starts requesting records. &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The client randomly selects a set of individual requesets and records from the session.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The client then checks the proofs of inclusion for each record it selected. 
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;If any of the proofs fails, it publishes enough information to its peers to reproduce the failure and it stops trusting the server.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;If the client recieves a failed audit from a peer, it stops trusting the server.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thus, with many active auditors the likelihood that a server can falsify or manipulate any record becomes extremely low.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;server-requirements-descriptions&quot;&gt;Server Requirements Descriptions&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;
1. Provide signed responses to all requests.
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is nessecary to sign every request from the server for the same reason https only works for a site if all traffic to the site is forced into https.
An attacker can selectively manipulate unsigned responses to specific API clients while those clients would not be able to discredit the API server.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The format of the signatures used is discussed in Section 6: &lt;a href=&quot;#Signatures&quot;&gt;Signatures&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;
2. Provide proofs of inclusion for all atomic records in its database.
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The server must provide the merkle path or an equivalent for each record it returns. 
This lets a client verify that any record requested is unmodified and placed within the block chain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;
3. Respond on a best effort basis to all requests from API clients.
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A malicious server could selectively respond to requests and simply return HTTP errors for things it does not want a client to view.
This means that an honest server must stay available and attempt to respond to every client request it gets.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Special care must be taken to balance DOS mitigation and valid challenges as an attacker could requests proofs only to discard them
in an attempt to waste server resources. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;client-requirements-descriptions&quot;&gt;Client Requirements Descriptions&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;
1. Select unpredictable challenges.
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If a malicious API server can predict the records the client is going to audit then it can lie through omission easily.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;
2. Regularly audit the API server.
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If a client does not check the proofs the server is delivering then there is no point in sending them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;
3. Publish failed audits to peers.
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This scheme relies on a sort of herd immunity to prevent anyone client from being lied to. 
If a client does not communicate or cannot communicate a failed proof to its peers then the entire herd is at risk.
Thus, it is imperative that peers remain in constant communication and they actively and quickly inform each other of malacious servers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;
4. Stop using the API server if it misbehaves or fails an audit.
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To function properly, clients should have next to no forgiveness for unresponsive API servers.
They should have &lt;strong&gt;no&lt;/strong&gt; trust in a server that fails an audit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;signatures&quot;&gt;Signatures&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This scheme requires API servers sign all of their json responses according to the JWS standard described in &lt;a href=&quot;https://tools.ietf.org/html/rfc7515&quot;&gt;RFC 7515&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;MORE&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;MORE&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;inclusion-proofs&quot;&gt;Inclusion proofs&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Each individual record can be provably demonstrated to be unchanged and included within the block chain.
An inclusion proof for our purposes is a merkle path that demonstrates that the record is included within the merkle root of a block that is in the block chain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;MORE&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;MORE&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;managing-certificates&quot;&gt;Managing Certificates&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While we are hesitant to make any reccomendations for or against a specific public key infrastructure.
The reference implementation will be using the standard defined in &lt;a href=&quot;https://tools.ietf.org/html/rfc5280&quot;&gt;RFC 5280&lt;/a&gt; where trusted root certificates are bundled with the application.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;LESS&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We do not have a novel solution for bootstrapping trust into this system and neither should you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;MORE &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;MORE&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;disclaimers&quot;&gt;Disclaimers&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are not cryptographers, but we believe we can construct secure systems.
That being said, it is important to dispell incorrect ideas about what this design makes possible.
This is not a complete list.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;
An API server only needs a few clients to audit it.
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The rate of challenges an API server must recieve is proportional to the size of the record. 
If the API server receives too few challenges then it can probabilistically get away with falsifying and omitting records.
Thus, if the size of the record grows so too must the number of auditors challenging the server.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;
API clients only need to check the proofs of records they are interested in.
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is possible and very likely that API servers will lie through omission, if they do not recieve enough random requests.
This is because a client cannot prove a record was left out of a response unless it has evidence of that record existing.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 30 Sep 2015 08:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>https://soapbox.systems/blog/2015/09/30/audit-api.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://soapbox.systems/blog/2015/09/30/audit-api.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>blog</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Some Press in Britain</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Alex and I were interviewed by &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/ajreid?lang=en&quot;&gt;Alistair Reid&lt;/a&gt;, a journalist at &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Journalism.co.uk&quot;&gt;Journalism.co.uk&lt;/a&gt;.
It was an interesting conversation. Go check out the resulting &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.journalism.co.uk/news/ombuds-using-bitcoin-to-make-online-messages-immutable-/s2/a566167/&quot;&gt;story&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 26 Aug 2015 17:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>https://soapbox.systems/blog/2015/08/26/journalism-co-uk.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://soapbox.systems/blog/2015/08/26/journalism-co-uk.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>blog</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Terms of our Present Work</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;In the spirit of openness and collaboration Soapbox we are disclosing the full terms
of &lt;a href=&quot;http://knightfoundation.org/grants/201551198/&quot;&gt;our grant&lt;/a&gt; with the Knight Foundation to the public. If in a line item interests 
you, feel free to reach out to us online or Nick specifically via email. 
We have set aside some money for supporting 
work on each item, we might be able to pay you for work that you want to do! 
Especially if you can do it better than us. Exciting stuff. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyway, here are the relevant bits verbatim from our agreement with Knight.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/res/knight/activities.png&quot; alt=&quot;Grant Activities&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/res/knight/outcomes.png&quot; alt=&quot;Grant Outcomes&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/res/knight/evals.png&quot; alt=&quot;Grant Evaluations&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 25 Aug 2015 17:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>https://soapbox.systems/announce/2015/08/25/funded.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://soapbox.systems/announce/2015/08/25/funded.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>announce</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Hello, World!</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;This website will serve as a place for collecting tidbits about our work across the web. Look to this site in times of leisure or information collection. Soapbox Systems was founded in September of 2014 with the explicit goal of creating open source software for the public good. Hopefully, our work demonstrates that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If anybody ever asks, we started out at &lt;a href=&quot;http://hackcville.com&quot;&gt;HackCville&lt;/a&gt; in Charlottesville Virginia. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/res/incorp.png&quot; alt=&quot;articles of incorp&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 01 Aug 2015 12:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>https://soapbox.systems/announce/2015/08/01/hello-world.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://soapbox.systems/announce/2015/08/01/hello-world.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>announce</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
